sibelius.com 2018-12-29

# Privacy Policy Statement - Avid

Avid Technology, Inc. has created this Privacy Policy Statement in order to inform you of our commitment to privacy and to describe our policies for the collection, use, and disclosure of personal information that may be collected by Avid when you visit our websites or use certain Avid products. In a few cases, Avid’s other websites may contain additional privacy policies. Your visits to those sites will be governed by the privacy policies, if any, that govern those sites.

PLEASE REVIEW THIS PRIVACY POLICY BEFORE USING THIS SITE. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH OUR PRIVACY POLICY, DO NOT USE THE SITE. BY SUBMITTING ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION TO THE SITE, YOU AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT.

Your use of this site is also subject to the Terms of Use. Please review those Terms of Use for additional details regarding your use of this site.

#### GENERAL INFORMATION

#### IP Addresses and Cookies

Generally speaking, you may visit the site while remaining anonymous and not revealing any personal information.

Our websites automatically log your IP address and domain name, and non-personal information such as the type of web browser you use, to help us administer the sites and to compile statistics such as the number of visitors.

Our websites use cookies to identify you over multiple visits to the site, for example to remember your country and provide country-specific content. Cookies are optional, and you can block or delete them. However, some parts of our websites (e.g. chat pages, Online Store) will not work without cookies. Cookies may also be used to track visitor behavior on the website, which allows visitors to be retargeted with digital advertising that reflects their past behavior on the site.

#### The Types of Cookies Avid Uses

Session cookies: These cookies are temporary and expire once you leave the site. Session cookies are mainly used by webshops to hold your items in the basket while you are shopping online.

Persistent cookies: Persistent cookies may stay on your disk for a long time after the session is ended. These cookies may hold data such as login details, contact information and account numbers, so that you don’t have to type them in every time you use the site.

Avid also permits third-party advertising partners to use cookies and other technology to collect information about your browsing activities over time and across different websites when you use our site. Through a process called “retargeting,” each service places a cookie on your browser when you visit our site so that they can identify you and serve you ads on other sites around the web based on your browsing activity.

For information on how to disable cookies on your computer, visit the Managing cookies page.

#### Submission of Personal Information

Certain portions of the site may require that you submit some personal information, such as your name and email address, before using those portions of the site. At minimum, you are typically required to register with the site and provide your name or email address before using any of the members only areas of the site. For some services, such as forums, the Avid Artist Community, customer support features, registering for events or contests, downloading software or uploading content, you may have to create an account, and submit additional personal information such as your mailing address.

#### Use of Personal Information

Avid uses information it collects to provide the services and information you select, to better understand its customers, to provide better products and services, and to assist with site administration, such as with troubleshooting any problems, detecting fraud, resolving disputes, and for any purposes deemed necessary or required by Avid to enforce the Terms of Use and other terms or conditions applicable to any portion of the site.

We also use this information to send you information about Avid, or other topics Avid thinks may be of interest to you, such as product information or updates. As part of its business, Avid works with authorized partners, such as authorized resellers, to provide you with the services and information. As part of those activities, Avid may share your information with those authorized entities so that they can directly provide the information or services to you.

The processing of your data is either based on your consent or in case the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party, or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract.

If the processing is based on your consent, you may at any time withdraw your consent by contacting us at [privacy@avid.com](mailto:privacy@avid.com) or the address listed below. This email address is for privacy related inquiries only. All other requests, such as for product support, will not be replied to. For product support and troubleshooting, please contact Avid Customer Care by clicking here.

In order to enter into a contract regarding the purchase of Avid’s products or services, you must provide us with the required personal data. If you do not to provide us with all the required information, it will not be possible to deliver the product or service.

Avid keeps the information you provide for as long as you remain an active user of the site and recipient of our information.

#### Aggregation and Use of Anonymous Data

Avid aggregates information provided by you to create anonymous statistical and demographic data. This anonymous data helps Avid to understand and know its customer base better. That anonymous data may be provided to third parties but never in such a fashion as to identify you personally.  Some Avid products and websites use Google Analytics for the collection of anonymous data. [Learn more about how Google uses data collected using Google Analytics.](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/ "Learn more about how Google uses data collected using Google Analytics.&nbsp;")

The Google Analytics features that Avid employs are as follows:

  * General Features related to browsing behavior such as: browser type/version and language, operating system type/version, device type/version, domains, page views, referring/exit pages, location data such as country, information about how you interact with our Site’s webpages and with third-party links, traffic and usage trends
  * Demographics and Interest Reports: Age, Gender, Interest Data
  * Advertising and Remarketing: This includes data from Google's signed-in users who have chosen to enable Google to associate their web and app browsing history with their Google account, and to use such information from their Google account to personalize ads
  * User ID Tracking: To combine sessions across multiple devices and interactions for logged-in users
  * Site Search Tracking: What a user typed into the sites search feature
  * eCommerce Tracking: Information related to product purchased, price, date and time of purchase, order #, etc.
  * Enhanced eCommerce Tracking: Information related to products viewed, products added/removed to cart, onsite promotions clicked, currency, refunds, etc.

You can opt out of Google Analytics by using this tool:  
<https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>

#### Third Parties

Avid does not sell to third parties information you have submitted to this site that identifies you personally.

On occasion, Avid may offer in conjunction with third parties certain services that may require you to share your personal information with that third party as a condition for receiving that service. In addition, if you purchase third party products on the Avid Online Store, Avid may share your information with the manufacturer of that product. While Avid will treat any information it receives in accordance with this Privacy Policy Statement, Avid will not be responsible for the information submitted by you to that third party, and we remind you to review the applicable rules and any third party's applicable privacy policies separately before participating in such service. Avid may also work with third party publishers and vendors to serve digital advertising across relevant sites on the Internet. Third party vendors may also use cookies to serve digital ads based on a person’s past visits to the Avid site.

#### Declining Information

You can opt out of receiving Avid marketing messages; see the Accept/Decline section below. Please note that it may take us a reasonable amount of time to process your request.

Even if you decline to receive information or cancel your account, Avid reserves the right to use the information you previously provided to provide you with the Avid products and services you are eligible to receive and to contact you about administrative matters relating to your use of any portion of the site, your account, or about any issues relating to the Terms of Use, this Privacy Policy, or any other policy then in-effect (for example, the Copyright Complaint Policy).

#### Public Forums for User Materials

Certain portions of the site are designed to offer you the opportunity to post information on the site, including but not limited to information about yourself ("User Materials"). You should always remember that publicly displayed information is public. For example, you may be permitted to post your resume information, a video you have created, or to post messages in any chat rooms, message boards, mailing lists, and/or news groups this site makes available to its users. If you use a forum, bulletin board or chat room on an Avid website you should be aware that any information you share is visible to other users. Personally identifiable information you submit to one of these forums can be read, collected, or used by other individuals to send you unsolicited messages. Avid is not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

Please see the Terms of Use for additional terms related to Avid’s forums and posting of User Materials.

#### Law Enforcement

As noted in the Terms of Use Avid intends to cooperate with any order or request from law enforcement officials or a court of competent jurisdiction for information as to the identity of individuals submitting or posting information to Avid or on this site. Such orders or requests supersede the terms of this Privacy Policy. Similarly, notifications of claimed copyright infringement, counter notifications or other information submitted to and necessary to process a notification under our Copyright Complaint Policy are also exempt from this Privacy Policy.

#### Avid Links to Other Sites and Advertising

This site may display advertisements and/or links to third parties. Avid is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those websites. Please refer to that company's privacy policy for further information.

#### Surveys

From time to time Avid may make online surveys available to users of the site. Participation in those surveys is voluntary. Some online surveys may ask participants for personal information, such as an email address, in addition to requesting answers to survey questions. Avid may use that personal information to contact the participant if necessary, or as otherwise described above. Avid may make the results of any survey publicly available, although Avid will not attribute any particular response to you without your permission.

#### Contests

On occasion Avid may make available to users of the site contests, sweepstakes, or similar events in which they may qualify for participation. Participation is always voluntary and subject to the applicable rules. The rules may ask participants to provide personal information as a condition of participation. Avid may also make the winner's names public, as provided in the applicable rules, or as required by law. Avid may also use that information as described above. In some instances, the applicable rules may contain additional or different uses for the information you provide; please be sure to review those rules carefully before entering.

Avid may permit a third party to sponsor a survey, contest, sweepstakes, or other similar event ("third party event") with Avid, such as through posting it on the site. Such third party events are governed solely by any applicable rules, and may require you to provide information to that third party as a condition for participation. While Avid will treat any information it receives in accordance with this Privacy Policy, Avid is not responsible for the information gathered by that third party, and Avid reminds you to review the rules and privacy policies separately applicable to those third party events.

#### CHILDREN

Some of Avid’s websites may appeal to or be intended for children; however, we do not wish to receive data from children. We encourage parents and guardians to spend time online with their children and to participate in the interactive activities offered on the sites their children visit. No information should be submitted to, or posted at, Avid’s website by visitors under 18 years of age without the consent of their parent or guardian. For sites that are intended for use by children we have put in place additional privacy practices which are described on those sites.

#### SUPPORT DATA

Support Data will be used only to provide customers with support, including purposes compatible with providing support, such as troubleshooting recurring issues and improvements to support or to products and services. Avid will not use Support Data or derive information from it for advertising or similar commercial purposes without customer’s permission.

#### SECURITY

#### General Issues

Generally speaking, this site has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. No security measures are 100% effective and Avid does not warrant the security of your personal information.  Since the site under general usage does not collect financial information, Avid uses the standard internet connections for those general usage portions of the site, without secured sockets.

#### Specific Services

This site may provide certain additional, optional services that may use additional security measures to protect the information, such as financial information, provided by you to obtain the service. Those additional security measures may vary, depending upon the particular service offered. You will be informed of any specific security measures at the time you register for a particular service. Please review that information for further detail.

#### Site Registration

In some cases, you may be prompted to register with the site to undertake a particular site activity or obtain a particular service. As part of that registration, you may be asked to choose your own password. Avid reminds you to protect your password, and not provide it to others to use. Allowing others to access and use your account and password can compromise the security of your information. Avid disclaims any responsibility or obligation for your decision to provide your password to others.

#### CHANGES TO THIS POLICY

If and when Avid makes changes to this site and its products and services, Avid may have to update this Privacy Policy Statement to better reflect those changes. Because changes to this site or updates to this Privacy Policy Statement may occur, you should review this Privacy Policy Statement from time to time. Remember, your decision to continue using this site after this Privacy Policy Statement is updated will signify that you have agreed to any new terms.

#### ACCEPT/DECLINE

Typically you accept to receive communications when you submit information to the site. If you wish to remove your information from the site registration database and no longer receive future communications or use any services, you may do so through any of the methods described below. Please note that it may take us a reasonable amount of time to process your request.

  1. The Profile section of this site may permit you to change a previous selection and decline to receive further communications, or to delete your registration.
  2. A particular service may have an Administration section that allows you to change any previous selections for that service.
  3. You can send an email to [privacy@avid.com](mailto:privacy@avid.com) for assistance in deleting/changing your prior selections.
  4. To manage marketing email content you receive from us, please [click here](https://connect.avid.com/Email-Preferences-Center.html). You may completely unsubscribe from marketing email communications anytime [here](https://connect.avid.com/Unsubscribe.html).

#### CORRECT/UPDATE

This site gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided.

  1. The Profile section of this site may permit a registered user to change or modify information previously provided.
  2. A particular service may have an Administration section that allows you to change or modify information you previously provided for that service.
  3. You can send an email to [privacy@avid.com](mailto:privacy@avid.com) for assistance in deleting/changing your prior selections.

#### RIGHTS UNDER THE GDPR

Avid is compliant with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Under that regulation, you have the right to (a) be informed about Avid’s use of your data, (b) to access the data Avid has collected from you, (c) to correct any mistakes in the data Avid has collected, (d) the right to have the data Avid has collected erased, (e) to restrict processing (f) to portability of the information Avid has collected, (g) to object to the collection and processing of information, and (h) to not be profiled. To exercise any of these rights, please contact Avid at [privacy@avid.com](mailto:privacy@avid.com) or via mail at the address below.

#### CONTACTING THE WEBSITE

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, you can contact the Data Privacy Officer at the following address and email:

**Data Privacy Officer**  
Avid Technology, Inc.  
75 Network Drive  
Burlington, MA 01803  
U.S.A   

#### NOTICE TO EUROPEAN USERS

Please note that the information you enter on the site or otherwise provide to Avid Technology, or its subsidiaries or divisions, may be transferred outside of the European Economic Area, for purposes of processing, by Avid Technology, Inc. a company located in Burlington, Massachusetts, U.S.A., or its subsidiaries or Avid's subsidiaries or divisions, or authorized partners, located worldwide, in order to provide this site and its services to you. You are advised that the United States uses a sectoral model of privacy protection that relies on a mix of legislation, governmental regulation, and self-regulation. You are further advised that the Council of the European Union has found that this model does not provide "adequate" privacy protections as contemplated by Article 25 of the European Union's Data Directive. (Directive 95/46/EC, 1995 O.J. (L 281) 31)

Article 26 of the European Union's Data Directive allows for transfer of personal data from the European Union to a third country if the individual has unambiguously given his consent to the transfer of personal information, regardless of the third country's level of protection.

By agreeing to this Policy, you consent to the transfer of all such information to the United States and the processing of that information as described in this Policy
